Boss, you know I'm about to graduate recently
Are all the leading semiconductor companies coming to our school to recruit people?
Why are you going to Semiconductor?
make money
shallow
You know it's ramming now when it's ramming
When the time comes he will lay off employees.
The ones who are being cut are you, the most talented people in the batch.
Otherwise I will mess with you
Fuck with me
Only then can we see the pattern of the entire industry chain
You see everyone is looking at the sky now
It feels like there is something in the sky
But don't know
People like us look at the ground
gold everywhere
Did you just step on shit?
Everyone is telling you about Taiwan’s super semiconductors
But have you ever thought about it
What do these things do to you?
Yes, what on earth are you doing to me?
In addition to buying stocks, do you
What else can you do
nothing nothing to do
Otherwise what else can I do?
but i tell you
This episode is to start everyone's
Imagination on industrial knowledge
Even if you are an old factory
small factory
traditional industry
You can all do this together
The production chain in semiconductors
how to do
welcome to watch
Industry from elementary school
Grow up and make a lot of money
super serious boy
You know I personally like to go to exhibitions very much
Because you went to the exhibition
In addition to visiting the major manufacturers,
those of us
Just look at
Surrounding industrial chains and supply chains
And sometimes you go to an automation exhibition
sometimes you look at something
You will apply it to the coffee show
coffee show
You use things from the coffee show
Sometimes you will see its logical structure design
You will use it in the machinery exhibition
Even used in semiconductor exhibition
You said its principle is universal
Even if you look
It's obviously a coffee exhibition
Coffee and Wine Exhibition
Sometimes there is something next to it
water filter
Selling filtered water
Look, who makes coffee without filtered water?
Oh boss boss
do you remember
Is that the air purifier we shot last time?
You said you were introducing the disassembled air purifier
i heard about them
After we finished shooting, they sold really well.
How good is it selling?
I don't know, but tens of millions
Selling tens of millions!?
Should I be given one?
Didn't even give it to me
yes
Hurry up and call!
Yes, look
Life needs to be filtered
Medical supplies also need to be filtered
yes
Have you ever thought about Semiconductor Exhibition
Semiconductor factory inside
Also filter
Semiconductors also need to be filtered
Do you know that in semiconductor
Under such high standards and requirements
what it wants to filter
Definitely different
You also know that in this world
There is a lot of garbage that needs to be filtered out
Why are you looking at me?
If not, it’s just impurities.
Things you don't need
in the air
Some are in life
So today we are going to show you
Just one
40 years old factory
After you finish reading
Maybe viewers
you will want to say
Maybe your factory can be changed to something like this
And after you finish reading
Maybe you will feel
In fact, semiconductors and your factory
A little bit related
There are all
Can't take it
I almost couldn't pick it up
It must be related
It's just that you didn't expect it
This is the best reason to hang out with me
Didn't mess with me
You can't see this vision
You don't know what to say
It turns out this thing
Since it can also become a semiconductor
So what you want today is
open my eyes
It’s not that we are talking nonsense
I will take you to see the factory right away
Today, your boss, I want to show you this company.
There is no need to use so many people in semiconductors
You can still earn billions every year
We have taken pictures of filtered water for you before
I also took everyone to see the two halls.
The kind that was left behind 40 years ago
German designed air conditioning system
But let me tell you
Today you are going to make a semiconductor air conditioning system
Completely different again
behind you
This thing looks like
Everyone looks very high-tech
But actually
we today
Just take it step by step
Teach everyone how to start from
little worker
All the way to achieve annual revenue of several billions
And you know this air conditioning system
It is not used to blow air conditioners in ordinary homes.
Otherwise, where would it be used?
AMC
boss boss
Wait a moment
let me
Highlights
Yes or no
you know
Almost poached by semiconductors
Yes, how could you not understand?
Tell you about AMC
AMC
Airborne Molecular Contamination
Micro air molecular pollutants
It is actually a general term
in semiconductor manufacturing process
There will be some spillage
Or some pollutants in gaseous and vaporous states
then it is covered
0.1nm to 10nm
What about these gaseous and vaporous pollutants?
In our wafer manufacturing process
will damage the wafer itself.
So is it possible to live a little more life-like?
Live a little more
like hair
Ten thousand nanometers
That virus like COVID
This hundred nanometers
like this
What do you mean?
I'm at least 18 centimeters, okay?
fiber of clothing
What is filtered in the clean room
Eyes different from those of us ordinary people
The standards you see are different
But don’t underestimate yourself
I feel like your company can’t do this business
In fact, there are many things that can be done in the semiconductor business
Okay, take a look here
clean room
Come let me tell you
follow me
You will see a different world
We're above the clean room now
So above the clean room
This negative pressure
Blow it all the way in
The place when the pressure becomes positive
right here
That's it
But you know
If you want to make money from semiconductors today
In addition to setting up a clean room, you can
You can also do this air conditioning system
But maybe you just need to be able to sell one thing.
sell this filter
So how do you make this filter?
Let's go into the factory
Yes, why does this thing look like this?
Probably very few people have seen its previous production process.
Have you used activated carbon for so long?
You probably haven’t seen what activated carbon really looks like, right?
Activated Carbon Baby Now
right in my spoon
activated carbon
Of course when filtering everything
You need to mix the ingredients. You need to stir.
Inside the gas you want to filter today
Acidic substances
Then you have to mix it
Alkaline materials
Acid-base neutralization
If I were to filter alkaline substances today
Then I'm going to put some acid in it.
That's right
So actually inside the filter material
There is one that can actually be recycled
Because of the way activated carbon absorbs
It actually uses a method like physics
physical means
What is the physical method called?
Adsorption
What about separation?
Desorption
oops
entrust my heart to you
No wonder I can go to work in semiconductors
So at this time
You have to according to the needs of your different fields
Then you will use different ingredients
then mix it
First let's add a little cleverness
Next, let’s add some industrial technology into it
Finally we add stupidity
Oh, I accidentally put too much
Hopeless
Wait until your ingredients are mixed
We can mix it
(stir)
(stirring completed)
After your ingredients are mixed?
We're going to put it now
On top of the material that ordinary people have the impression of
What
non-woven fabric
Non-woven fabrics are like what we see behind us now
This toilet paper roll
We've never done anything like that
Is the factory for paper and cloth materials correct?
You mean toilet paper?
Roar that
Very handsome
I'll shoot another episode for you all when I get a chance.
You'll also see toilet paper like rollers in the front
Same here
Then follow this order
Sprinkle the first layer of powder first
That first layer of powder
It depends on what kind of material you want to filter before.
You can put the first layer you want to filter
First put it on a layer inside the non-woven fabric
You can also make it a composite
Oh yes
After one level, go to the back
you can continue
Sprinkle on the activated carbon we just mixed
After mixing the black activated carbon
Let's go on
we're going to heat it up
to glue it together
Because like we just were
When doing it simply over there
Actually more or less
There will be some airborne dust floating there.
So you see why you don’t wear a mask?
That's the reason
What's the meaning
Because we have to shoot a movie
It will be covered with another layer of cloth later
So it's equal to three layers
Then clamp two ingredients
One is activated carbon
Then the other one is watching
Are you acidic or alkaline?
Yes comprehensive
So inside the filter element
why it
Different filter elements have different prices
It’s also because the ingredients that need to be filtered are different.
What it can do is different
So of course its cost and materials are also different.
So look
You see now from the front
All machinery and all production lines
Have you recorded it in your brain?
Isn't it difficult at all?
Let's look down
on our side
After all three layers are sandwiched
After adding everything you want to use,
you can then in the last section
Like our total width
About 155 centimeters
When you cut it into one, two, three and four
So a section of it is equivalent to
38.75 cm
These two next to
Because at these two edges,
Sometimes the material or powder on the side
it would be a little less
So just cut it off
Then you have to look at how old you want it to be.
Then you can weigh yourself here
After weighing
You can proceed to the next step
Here comes the discount
You see here is the discount area
That is to say, the machine operates with up and down movements.
Let your original spread of non-woven fabrics sit inside
into a variety of continuous W shapes
You must want to say
Why should we give discounts when everything is fine?
Why is your boss okay?
We're going to have a big auction off the building.
Why
In order to reach more people
with more air
After the W shape is completed
Next we have to go to the bonding area
The discount is over
Now the last thing is to make it
welt
To weld the edges, just use the high-temperature glue on the side.
Glue the edges together
After gluing it up, you will see it look like this
grid by grid
Do you know what that comb is for?
jig
We just got a discount
On sale you need to stick it to the side W
If you stick it well
Afraid of getting soft
So take a comb and comb it to the side like this
You stick to me when I'm around
It has a beautiful W on every side
it is fixing its spacing
These are the things you see
In many high-tech factories
above the ceiling
For example, they use that kind of centrifugal fan to blow it down
The working environment inside is positive pressure
Then there is negative pressure above
So it needs negative pressure air
When I want to come over here
like this
You can switch row by row
So every once in a while
When it feels the air is bad
Time is up
Then we can change the filter element
But do you think
This matter is a bit troublesome
The hand is slowly getting sticky over there.
Let’s show you the presentation of automation
(automatic glue)
(Install outer frame)
(Adhere the sealing strip)
(Packed and shipped)
These filters after shipment
due to different environments
Have different expiration dates
So what happens after the expiration date?
They will recycle all these filters
Not only the outer frame of the filter can be reused
the fabric inside it
Can also be reused ten times
Isn’t it very environmentally friendly?
The filter after we came back with the recycling truck
Now we're going to actually recycle it.
ok how to recycle
There's an oven in the back to burn it
Clam
Our world hopes to achieve a
The concept of net zero carbon reduction
So before we used up the filter,
what to do
Just burn it
Or take it and throw it away
But you throw this away
it will produce garbage
produce a lot of pollution
So there is a way to recycle
Just heat it up
thermal dissociation
Hot flow regeneration technology
That's right
You just throw it in this oven
Then what
Repeatedly raise and lower the temperature
after
The dirt on it will be blown away
so
so we can
Reuse this filter 10 times
Then
Then we can achieve
Net zero carbon emissions by 2050
To sum up
In summary
This is one
Excellent method to achieve energy saving and carbon reduction
Not bad
Grow up
Oh, grown up
necessary
So at this moment
You're on top of this clean room
What you see
Just earlier
Brother
Dig it out on that one.
The filter inside is opened
That filter has been used for a long time
It's always going to be dirty
When you get dirty, come here
rearrange
After finishing, go back and use it again
It can go back and forth like this
Repeat until it can't be repeated anymore
If you want to be a supplier today
You can also help your boss and help you as an owner
Come up with something like this
Developing towards green manufacturing
so you see
Why go to work in semiconductors?
You come and go to different companies
Go help others come up with a new set of logic
your customers
Not just a leader in semiconductors
So even his hostile opponents
They will all be your customers
Clam
so i can earn more
shallow
But of course there is more to filtering than just that
There is another way
filter cartridge
When everyone pays more and more attention to recycling
There is another kind
Chemical filter form of cartridge filtration
That's the filter cartridge
The way the filter cartridge is used is inside
You can add various types of activated carbon
Various formulas you want to neutralize acid and alkali
After using it, filter it
after invalid
Take it out, pour it out and wash it
Put it back and it can be used again
But the recycling and production methods of filter cartridges
It's just not the same as you imagined
Then we'll take you inside to see
(Clean and recycle filter cartridge)
(filler)
(Install the upper cover)
(RFID scan)
These recycled filter cartridges
After filling again
it can be shipped again
You just need to scan the RFID before shipping
After logging in these production history systems,
Filter cartridge production date
Basic information of filter cartridge
Filter cartridge production serial number
Filter cartridge cycle times
This way you won’t reuse the old filter cartridge.
It's like every filter cartridge
There will be an ID card, which means the same thing.
Saw so much
are you concerned about
How to join semiconductor and make big money
This thing is more imaginative
If you haven't seen enough
You can go to SEMICON Taiwan 2024
Come and see more exhibitions
This year’s SEMICON Taiwan
On September 4th
Grand opening in Hall 1 and Hall 2 of Nangang Exhibition Hall
This year’s exhibition will feature Breaking Limits
Powering the AI Era
Empower AI without limits as the main axis
Discover the keys to driving the AI ​​era
semiconductor technology
At this scene
More than 1,100 manufacturers will soon be gathered
An estimated 85,000 people will participate
This year’s exhibition exhibitors gather together again
Contains complete
Artificial intelligence chip manufacturing supply chain
There are also popular ones now
CoWoS supply chain vendors
Of course there is more important
Sustainable green manufacturing solutions provider
circular economy
High-tech factory facilities
Smart energy management
and carbon management
And the filter material manufacturer we photographed today
What about Yuxiang Enterprise?
They will also be in the circular economy zone
Show more content together
What about friends who are interested?
You can see it in the information column below
There is a lottery for tickets
So whether you are today
Friends in the semiconductor industry
Or you want to join industry
and want another way
Then go to the people who enter this industry
(The exhibition is free to visit)
You are all welcome to watch this exhibition
So here is this week’s super serious boy
See you next week
Goodbye
What kind of gesture is this?
That's it
You have to talk about this like you're talking about it in a nightclub
Lucky draw in the information column below
How can you go like this?
You want to be a cadre somewhere else
Just have to look decent
How about a few more years of study?
This requires training
Goodbye, Chairman
Goodbye Chairman
Goodbye
So when you see it put up
You face this below
Then let go of your hands gently like this
Will suck
You see it sucking, this suction feeling
Will suck, will suck
Negative pressure
negative pressure negative pressure
This is how it feels when you breathe it in